Guide to the Roman Gulʹ Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1900-66; Series II; 9.25; (24 boxes)
  - NOVYI ZHURNAL
    - Av'erino, Konstantin K.: "Tiflis", [1953?] (Box 31, Folder 711)
    - Bakunina, N.
      See: IArtseva, N., Box 27, folder 597
    - Balakan, Boris: "Upavshie list'ia.. .", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 712)
    - Balashov, Mikhail Ivanovich
      See: Nil'skii, Mikhail Ivanovich, Box 39, folder 950
    - Baratynskii, Viacheslav Vladimirovich
      See: Lensky, Sergio, Box 37, folder 895
    - Barnatnyi, Nikolai
      See: Gepshtein, S., Box 34, folder 796
    - Bashevis, Isaak
      See: Singer, Isaak Bashevis, Box 43, folder 1072
    - Bel'deninov, Sergei I.: "Komu zhivetsia veselo, vol'gotno v SSSR", 1952 (Box 31, Folder 713)
    - Beloborodov, Andrei IA.: "Vospominaniia" (Box 31, Folder 714-18)
    - Benderov, Konstantin D.: "Iz vstrech i vospominanii" (Box 31, Folder 719)
    - Benningsen, Emmanuil
      - "K stat'e 'Porazhenstvo i vlasovtsy' Dvinova", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 720)
      - "Po-povodu 'Vospominanii' o. Protopresvitera A. Shavel'skogo", 1955 (Box 31, Folder 721)
    - Berberova, Nina Nikolaevna: "Smert' Anny Grigor'evny", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 722)
    - Berger, IAkov Iosifovich: "Ona byla vrachem v trushchobakh", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 723)
    - Berger, Iosif: "Vospominaniia o Roskol'nikove", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 724)
    - Berlin, Pavel Abramovich: "P. N. Miliukov, G. V. Plekhanov, Lenin i evreiskii vopros v Rossii", 1963 (Box 31, Folder 725)
    - Beryshkin, Pavel Afanas'evich: "Monsieur Philippe, predshestvennik Rasputina", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 726)
    - Bogatyrchuk, Fedor Parfen'evich: "Voprosy etiki i morali u uchastnika Osvoboditel'nogo dvizheniia narodov Rossii", 1955 (Box 32, Folder 727)
    - Bogoiavlenskaia, Marianna: "O Valerii Tarsise", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 728)
    - Bondarenko, Vladimir Ivanovich: "Iz t'my vekov" (Box 32, Folder 729)
    - Buchinskii, B.: "Strategiia tret'ei mirovoi voiny", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 730)
    - Buldeev, Aleksandr Ivanovich: "Oleg Il'inskii", [1962] (Box 32, Folder 731)
    - Bunin, Ivan Alekseevich: "'Noch'. Iskushenie, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 732)
    - Burova, Nina: "O psikhologii Dostoevskogo v 'Brat'iakh Karamazovykh'", 1955 (Box 32, Folder 733)
    - Burtsev, Vladimir L'vovich
      - "My arrest on the first day of the Bolshevik revolution", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 734)
      - "Return to Russia in 1914", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 735)
    - Buryshkin, Pavel Afanas'evich: "Monsieur Phillippe, predshestvennik Rasputina", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 736-38)
    - Bylinkina, Mariia
      - "Leningrad pred voinoi i v nachale voiny", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 739-43)
      - "Tol'ko piat' let; zapiski iz zhizni... zhenshchiny iz Sovetskogo Soiuza", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 744-51)
    - Chapka, S.: "Talant razmenivaemyi na pokaianiia", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 752)
    - Chebotareva-Bill, V. P.: "Sergei Timofeevich Aksakov", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 753)
    - Chekhonin, Mikhail Georgievich: "Sluchai", 1952 (Box 32, Folder 754)
    - Cheldon, Ivan Emel'ianovich
      - "Nauchnaia dezinformatsiia o Sovetskom Soiuze", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 755)
      - "Regressivnaia evoliutsiia", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 756)
    - Chernosvitova, Mariia Vasil'evna: "Chernigov: to chto ia znaiu i pomniu o nem", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 757)
    - Chernov, V. M. (Viktor Mikhailovich): "Vozmozhna li v Rossii demokratiia", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 758)
    - Davnii, Boris: "Vstrecha; p'esa", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 759)
    - Deshart, Ol'ga: "Posleslovie-primechanie", 1962 (Box 33, Folder 760)
    - Desnianskii, S.: "O dobroi vole, porozhdaiushchei zlo", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 761)
    - Diamandi, Ivan
      - "Bor'ba so smert'iu", [1951] (Box 33, Folder 762)
      - "Iz arkhiva Velikoi voiny" i " V gostiakh u generalisimusa", 1945, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 763)
      - "Novaia kvartira", "Za sovetskuiu rodinu", 1951, [1961?] (Box 33, Folder 764)
    - Dobrovol'skii, A.
      - "Dve svobody", [1960] (Box 33, Folder 765)
      - "'Sotsialisticheskaia' fal'sifikatsiia nauky", [1955] (Box 33, Folder 766)
    - Donskoi, Nikita: "Iz tsikla 'Tiuremnye vstrechi'", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 767)
    - Du, Agrippina: "Po toi-zhe doroge", 1950-56 (Box 33, Folder 768-69)
    - Dymov, Osip
      See: Perel'man, Osip Isidorovich, Box 40, folder 982
    - Dzhunkovskii, Leonid D.
      - "V poslednie gody imperatorskoi Rossii; roman", 1955 (Box 33, Folder 770-74)
      - "Zarisovki", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 775)
    - Ebner, Vol'fgang, von: "IUrii Arbatskii", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 776)
    - Elkin, Mikhail: "Nemnogo o literaturnykh podtasovkakh", 1952 (Box 33, Folder 777)
    - English, Kyra
      - "Na kurort", 1965 (Box 33, Folder 778)
      - "Neokonchenyi roman", 1965 (Box 33, Folder 779)
    - Ershov, Petr E.: "'Vchera' i 'Zavtra'; tsep' rasskazov", 1951-54 (Box 33, Folder 780-82)
    - Evangulov, Georgii (Box 34)
      - "Igra; roman", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 783-85)
      - "Korsikanskaia poema", 1960 (Box 34, Folder 786)
      - "Oganes, prodavets korov; p'esa", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 787)
    - Evreinov, N. N. (Nikolai Nikolaevich): "Ne khvalis' iduchi na rat'", 1951 (Box 34, Folder 788)
    - Fogel'man, L.: "Tvorchestvo Isaaka Bashevisa-Zingera", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 789)
    - Gagarin, Evgenii Andreevich
      - "Rossiia i Evropa", [1947] (Box 34, Folder 790)
      - "Rus'", 1947 (Box 34, Folder 791)
    - Galin, Aleksandr: "Problema arabskikh bezhentsev", [195-?] (Box 34, Folder 792)
    - Gareli, Izrail': "Vospominaniia i vstrechi. Voina i ssylka v Kazakhstan", [1961?] (Box 34, Folder 793-94)
    - Gefter, Aleksandr A.: "Formennoe pal'to", 1951 (Box 34, Folder 795)
    - Gepshtein, S.
      - "Dialog ob Agrippe", 1955 (Box 34, Folder 796)
      - "Otryvok iz romana", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 797-98)
    - Gippius, Z. N. (Zinaida Nikolaevna)
      - "Ob"ektivnyia zametki. (O evreiakh)", 1939 (Box 34, Folder 799)
      - "Poslednii krug", 1942 (Box 34, Folder 800)
      - "Prezhde. Teper'", 1940 (Box 34, Folder 801)
    - Glinka, Gleb
      - "Kriticheskie zamechaniia... ", 1953 (Box 34, Folder 802)
      - "O vere Khrystovoi i nashem iskustve", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 803)
    - Gorelov, Vsevolod: "F. F. Komissarzhevskii. Gody raboty v Sovetskoi Rossii", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 804)
    - Gorskaia, Antonina: "M. L. Gofman: pushkinoved", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 805)
    - Gorskii, O.
      - "Koleso progressa", [1952?] (Box 34, Folder 806)
      - "Pol'za mesta rozhdeniia i vred knigopechataniia", [1952] (Box 34, Folder 807)
    - Graf, Garal'd Karlovich: "Imperatorskii baltiiskii flot. Vypiska iz glavy 4-oi", [1954] (Box 34, Folder 808)
    - Grebenshchikov, Georgii: "Chto pervoe uvideli glaza?", "Shakhter i pakhar'" [dve glavy iz "Egorkina zhizn"], n.d. (Box 34, Folder 809)
    - Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich: "Lermontov u spiritov", 1952 (Box 34, Folder 810)
    - Gumileva, Anna Andreevna
      See: Akhmatova, Anna Andreevna, Box 30, folder 671
    - Guzenko, Igor': "[Padenie titana; roman] Dva otryvka", [1954?] (Box 35, Folder 811)
    - Hapgood, Elizabeth (Reynolds): "Friends of Sergius Vassilev and his beloved Tamara" (Box 35, Folder 812)
    - IAgotyn'skyi, Roman
      - "Kar'era Chubura; povest'", [1954] (Box 35, Folder 813-16)
      - "Platon Koshuba; otryvok", [1955] (Box 35, Folder 817)
    - IAkobson, Roman Osipovich
      See: Jakobson, Roman, Box 35, folder 834
    - IArtseva, N.: "Zapiski sestry", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 818-19)
    - IAsnyi, Naum: "V. G. Groman", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 820)
    - Il'inskaia, Natal'ia Aleksandrovna: "Vystavka kartin P. S. Korina", 1965 (Box 35, Folder 821)
    - Iordanskii, Mikail IUr'evich: "Baku i Poti v dekabre 1918 goda", [1952] (Box 35, Folder 822)
    - Iovlev, Georgii Fedorovich
      - "Krasnyi sud", [1963] (Box 35, Folder 823)
      - "'Patriotizm Ul'ianova-Lenina s sorvannoi maskoi", [1963] (Box 35, Folder 824)
    - Isheev, Petr Petrovich, kniaz': "V Kurliandii", "V Varshave", "V Petrograde", [1953?] (Box 35, Folder 825)
    - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich: "[O Mendel'shtame]" (Box 35, Folder 826)
    - Ivanov, Pavel: "Golosovali li vy za eto?", [1950] (Box 35, Folder 827)
    - Ivanov, Petr Konstantinovich: "Taina russkoi tserkvi", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 828)
    - [Ivanov?], V.: "I. A. Berdiaev i ego filosofiia tvorchestva, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 829)
    - Ivanov, V. I. (Viacheslav Ivanovich)
      - "Iz rimskogo dnevnika 1944 goda", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 830)
      - "K probleme zvukoobraza u Pushkina", 1925 (Box 35, Folder 831)
    - Ivask, George: "V poiskakh druga", [1959] (Box 35, Folder 832-33)
    - Izgoi, pseud.
      See: Bel'deninov, Sergei I., Box 31, folder 713
    - Izhorskii, Aleksei
      See: Zakharov, Aleksei Alekseevich, Box 47, folder 1154
    - Jakobson, Roman: "Izuchenie slavianskikh iazykov i literatury v sovremennoi Amerike", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 834)
    - Kalikin, Evegenii Vasil'evich: " Pod piatoi bol'shevizma v lageriakh Di-Pi", [1953] (Box 35, Folder 835-39)
    - Kalita, Nikolai (Box 36)
      - "K voskresen'iu'" "Seryi den'", "Ispytan'e liubvi'", 1948-56 (Box 36, Folder 840)
      - "Tri peomy, dva stikhotvoreniia", 1955-56 (Box 36, Folder 841)
    - Kalninsh, Al'bert: "O velikikh mirovykh zagadkakh... ", [1957] (Box 36, Folder 842)
    - Kaminskii, S.: "V staroi Anglii: putevnye vpechatleniia, [1960] (Box 36, Folder 843)
    - Karov, D.
      - "Otobrazhenie roli partizanskoi voiny i partizan... ", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 844)
      - "Ved'ma", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 845)
    - Kashin, Aleksandr Adrianovich
      - "Na grebne volny", 1955 (Box 36, Folder 846)
      - "Pis'mo iz Stalingrada", 1956 (Box 36, Folder 847)
    - Kashina-Evreinova, Anna Aleksandrovna: "Leto u Maksa Voloshina (Box 36, Folder 848)
    - Kaznov, I. P.: "Syn Volgi", 1954 (Box 36, Folder 849)
    - Khadzhiev, Razak Bek, Khan: "[General L. G. Kornilov]", [1957] (Box 36, Folder 850-54)
    - Kiparisov, A.: "Bekir Choban-Zade, poet krimskikh tatar", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 855)
    - Klimov, E.: "'Osnovy khudozhestva'. Kniga prof. I. A. Il'ina", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 856)
    - Kobiakov, Mikhail Vasil'evich: "Russkie v Chekhoslovakii, 1920-1951", 1955 (Box 36, Folder 857-58)
    - Kochevitskii, Georgii Andreevich
      - "V aprele-mae 1941 goda", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 859)
      - "Zhutkie dni", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 860)
    - Kodzhomberdiev, Kudaibergen: "Kak ia poekhal, chto tam vidal", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 861)
    - Kokoshkin, Vladimir Fëdorovich: "Vospominaniia o F. F. Kokoshkine", [1961] (Box 36, Folder 862)
    - Kolosov, Mikhail: "Kommunisticheskaia partiia i sovetskaia armiia", 1953 (Box 36, Folder 863-64)
    - Kol'tsov, Petr: "Khristianstvo i pravoslavie", 1955 (Box 36, Folder 865)
    - Konovalov, Evgenii Davidovich: "'Slovo o polku Igoreve'; razbor teksta", 1952 (Box 36, Folder 866)
    - Kormazov, V.: "Mongol'skii Lurd", [1953?] (Box 36, Folder 867)
    - Korshun, Gr.: "Bez viny", 1961 (Box 36, Folder 868)
    - Korson, Mikhail Georgievich
      - "Moe mirovozrenie", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 869)
      - "Oskol'ki d'iavol'skogo zerkala", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 870)
    - Korvin-Piotrovskii, Vladimir L'vovich
      - "Groza", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 871)
      - "Nezakhodiashchee solntse', n.d. (Box 36, Folder 872)
      - "O poezii i o prochem", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 873)
      - "Schast'e", n.d. (Box 36, Folder 874)
    - Kostylev, N.: "Pochemu i kak ponimanie refleksologii zaderzhalos'", 1958 (Box 37, Folder 875)
    - Kovarskaia, Lidiia Antonovna: "Dvizhenie russkoi molodezhi v narod... ", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 876)
    - Krasovskii, D. M.; "S. F. Platonov", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 877)
    - Krasuskii, Igor'
      - "Fazany", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 878)
      - "Kazennik", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 879)
      - "Okhotnich'e serdtse", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 880)
      - "S sokolom za gusiami", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 881)
    - Kripton, Konstantin
      - "Politika sovetskogo pravitel'stva v serenykh natsional'nykh raionakh... ", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 882)
      - "Vysshie uchebnye zavedeniia sovetskogo gosudarstva", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 883)
    - Krylov, B.
      - "Otkrytoe pis'mo k russkoi obshchestvennosti", [1952] (Box 37, Folder 884)
      - "Peremeny", [1955] (Box 37, Folder 885)
    - Kutyrina, IUliia Aleksandrovna
      - "[Tragediia I. S. Shmeleva]", 1953 (Box 37, Folder 886)
      - "Druzhba K. D. Bal'monta i Iv. Serg. Shmeleva", [1953?] (Box 37, Folder 887)
    - Lebedev, Sergei
      - "Kolo", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 888-93)
      - "Vstrechi", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 894)
    - Lensky, Sergio: "Tragediia russkogo pisatelia", [1958?] (Box 37, Folder 895)
    - Leshko, O.
      - "Iz letopisi proshlogo", [1962] (Box 37, Folder 896)
      - "Oskol'ki proshlogo", [1962] (Box 37, Folder 897)
    - Lesnoi, Sergei: "Chto predstavliala soboi 'vlasovshchina'?", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 898)
    - Levin, D.: "Na kom otvetstvennost' za pervuiu mirovuiu voinu" (Box 37, Folder 899)
    - Levitskii, Sergei Aleksandrovich: "S. L. Frank" (Box 37, Folder 900)
    - Levshin, Mikhael: "Professor Makarov", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 901)
    - Liaskovskii, Aleksandr: "Russkoe masonstvo v nemetskom osveshchenii" (Box 37, Folder 902)
    - Lidin, Mikhail: "Iz blatnogo mira v SSR; rasskaz", 1955 (Box 38, Folder 903)
    - Liutich, Martin
      - "Belorusskaia literatura", 1952 (Box 38, Folder 904-05)
      - "Na sibirskoi doroge", 1951 (Box 38, Folder 906)
      - "Sovetskoe kino", 1952 (Box 38, Folder 907)
    - Lunts, Lev
      - "[Puteshestvie na bol'nichnoi koike", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 908)
      - "Vosstanie veshchei. Kinostsenarii... ", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 909-12)
      - "Zaveshchan'e [!] tsaria. Stsenarii", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 913-14)
    - L'vov, Lollii: "Askol'dov, 1871-1945", 1962 (Box 38, Folder 915-16)
    - Lysenko, Nikolai I.
      - "Komandarm; iz vospominanii" (Box 38, Folder 917)
      - "Nevol'niki", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 918)
      - "Vospitannik", 1954 (Box 38, Folder 919)
      - "Vstrecha z zakliuchennymi, 1940", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 920)
      - M. R.: "Problema Indo-Kitaia" (Box 38, Folder 921)
    - Mabo-Azovskii, Mikhail: "Vospominaniia prikazchika, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 922)
    - Mackiewicz, Józef
      - "Pobeda provokatsii", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 923)
      - "Uvazhaemyi Mikhail Aleksandrovich [Sholokhov]", 1954 (Box 38, Folder 924)
    - MacReady, Anatolii Grigor'evich: "Zavidnaia smert'", [1963] (Box 38, Folder 925)
    - Makovskii, Sergei Konstantinovich: "Nikolai Gumilev... Po lichnym vospominaniiam", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 926-27)
    - Manasevich, V.: "Mysli bol'nogo soldata", 1953 (Box 38, Folder 928)
    - Manukhin, Ivan Ivanovich
      - "Otryvok iz vospominanii", 1940 (Box 38, Folder 929)
      - "Revoliutsiia", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 930)
    - Margolin, IUlii
      - "O svobode", 1951 (Box 38, Folder 931)
      - "Vitol'da Gombrovicha teatr marionetok... ", [1953?] (Box 38, Folder 932)
    - Margulies, IUrii M.: "Skupoi rytsar' i ego istochniki", 1955 (Box 39, Folder 933)
    - Markov, IUrii: "Matros Dybenko", [1958] (Box 39, Folder 934)
    - Matveev, Leonid Aleksandrovich: "Begstvo imp. Aleksandra I. na angliiskoi iakhte", [1959?] (Box 39, Folder 935)
    - Meier, A.: "Bakunin i Marks", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 936-37)
    - Meier, Pavel: "Starets Zosima", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 938)
    - Menskii, R.
      - "O knizhke", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 939)
      - "Partiia i literatura", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 940)
    - Meshcherskii, Boris Alekseevich, kniaz': "O Pravoslavnoi ikone", 1955 (Box 39, Folder 941)
    - Mezhakov, Igor': "Muzyka i poeziia v zhizni Pasternaka", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 942)
    - Mishalov, IUrii: "Kharakternaia detal' v povyshenii proizvoditel'nosti truda v SSSR", 1955 (Box 39, Folder 943)
    - Mizar, I.
      See: Zdorovets, Ivan, Box 47, folder 1161
    - Mren, E.: "Demokratiia i kommunizm", [1957] (Box 39, Folder 944)
    - Naglovskii, Aleksandr Dmitrievich: "Vstrechi s Leninym" (Box 39, Folder 945)
    - Nekrasov, Vladimir Alekseevich
      - "Vidimoe i nevidimoe v poletakh satelitov letom 1957 g." (Box 39, Folder 946)
      - "Za zheleznym runom", 1955 (Box 39, Folder 947)
    - Nevskii, Nikolai: "[V okruzhenii]", [1955?] (Box 39, Folder 948)
    - Nikitin, V.: "Natsional'nyi sostav naseleniia soiuznykh respublik SSSR, po perepisi 1939 g.", 1952 (Box 39, Folder 949)
    - Nikol'skii, Mikhail Ivanovich: "'Ukhodtsy. Glava iz... knigy Pobeg, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 950)
    - Nil'skii, Mikhail Ivanovich
      - "A. IA. Vyshinskii", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 951)
      - "Golova", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 952)
      - "Kamen zagovoril", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 953)
      - "Na vokzale", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 954)
      - "Partizany", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 955)
      - "Zoloto chesnogo printsa", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 956)
    - Nol'de, Aleksandr Emil'evich, baron: "Graf M. M. Speranskii" (Box 39, Folder 957)
    - Obol'ianinova, Sof'ia Aleksandrovna: "Stranitsy iz zhizni", 1960 (Box 39, Folder 958-59)
    - Odarchenko, IUrii: "Vorob'i", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 960)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna: "Na beregakh Nevy", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 961-63)
    - Ofrosimov, IUrii Viktorovich: "Vostavshie skol'niki", [1954] (Box 40, Folder 964)
    - Ol'khovskii, Andrei Vasil'evich: "Na khlebe stradanii i vode strakha" (Box 40, Folder 965)
    - Ol'shanskii, Boris
      - "Na rodine", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 966)
      - "Poslednie dni voiny", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 967)
    - Orem, Sergei: "Nikolai Semenovich Leshkov... ", [1954] (Box 40, Folder 968)
    - Orlov, Nikolai A.: "Berlin, 1 avgusta 1921" [dnevnik: 1 avg. 1921--29 avg. 1922], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 969)
    - Osipov, Nikolai Ivanovich: "O chem molchat statisticheskie tablitsy?", [1961] (Box 40, Folder 970)
    - Ozy, G.: "V shato. Romansirovanyi ocherk" (Box 40, Folder 971-74)
    - P. E. N.: "Memorandum on Visit of General Secretary to Moscow", [1966?] (Box 40, Folder 975)
    - Pastak, I. A.
      - "Put' na iug", [1961] (Box 40, Folder 976-77)
      - "Stoletie anilinovykh krasok, 1856-1956", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 978)
    - Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich: "Mne vypalo bol'shoe... shchast'e", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 979)
    - Pasternak, Zhosefina: "[L. O. Pasternak rodilsia... v Odesse... ]", [1962] (Box 40, Folder 980)
    - Pavlov, A.: "Ne suisia", [1957] (Box 40, Folder 981)
    - Perel'man, Osip Isidorovich: "Lik Dostoevskogo", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 982)
    - Permiakov, L.: "Unichtozhenie sovetami pol'skikh partizan", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 983)
    - Persidskaia, Lidiia: "K tridtsatiletiiu prinuditel'noi kollektivizatsii v SSSR", 1961 (Box 40, Folder 984)
    - Petrov, Viktor P.: "Polkovnik Iks", [1958] (Box 40, Folder 985)
    - Petrov-Skitalets, Evgenii Stepanovich
    - Petrovskii, N.: "Sovetskoe ugolovnoe pravosudie", 1955 (Box 40, Folder 986-87)
    - Pilenko, A.: "Deti i ottsy", 1952 (Box 40, Folder 988-92)
    - Pogorelova, Bronislava Matveevna: "Briusov v russkoi rubashke", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 993)
    - Polivanov, M. P.: "Vysshie uchebnye zavedeniia v pervye gody sovetskoi vlasti" (Box 40, Folder 994-95)
    - Pomerantsev, Kirill Dmitrievich: "Vladimir Smolenskii i ego peoziia", [1962] (Box 41, Folder 996)
    - Pozdniakov, Vladimir Vasil'evich: "Vozniknoevenie i gibel' partizanskogo otriada Sokolova", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 997)
    - Pronin, Dimitrii
      - "Ocherk sotsializatsii sel'skogo khozaistva Chekhoslovakii", [1953?] (Box 41, Folder 998)
      - "Russkie v nemetskoi armii na vostochnom fronte vo vremia 2oi Mirovoi voiny" [Vlasov], n.d. (Box 41, Folder 999)
    - Rachinskaia, Elena Nikolaevna: "Moi drug Shigeno", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1000)
    - Rafal'skii, Sergei
      - "Iskushenie Ottsa Afanasiia", 1954 (Box 41, Folder 1001-02)
      - "Vo edinu ot subbot", 1954 (Box 41, Folder 1003)
    - Rakhalov, Al.: "[Vorkuta]", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1004-06)
    - Ranevskii, Boris: "O Esenine", [1955] (Box 41, Folder 1007)
    - Rannit, Aleksis
      - "O Viacheslave Ivanove i ego 'Svete vechernem'", [1964?] (Box 41, Folder 1008-09)
      - "Pis'mennoe interv'iu s Vladimirom Korvinym-Piotrovskim", [1964] (Box 41, Folder 1010)
    - Redlikh, R. N.: "K voprosu o prirode bol'shevizma", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1011)
    - Remizov, Aleksei
      - "Gogolevskaia troika", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1012)
      - "Nozdrëv", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1013)
      - "Skvoz' pepel'no-sinii durman. Manilov", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1014)
      - "Voskreshenie mertvykh..", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1015)
    - Riazantseva, Anna: "Nadia", 1950 (Box 41, Folder 1016)
    - Rodnoi, N.: "Sovetskaia Bukhara", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1017)
    - Romanov, Boris Georgievich
      - "Kratkie ocherki iz istorii baleta", [1957] (Box 41, Folder 1018)
      - "Ocherki iz istorii baleta: S. P. Diagilev", [1957] (Box 41, Folder 1019)
    - Ronseval', Mariia: "Mirosozertsanie A. I. Gerstena", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1020)
    - Rubanov, Leo Stepanovich: "Teatr L. B. IAvorskogo i klub 'Mednyi vsadnik'", [1964] (Box 41, Folder 1021)
    - Rusanov, V.
      See: Manasevich, V., Box 38, folder 928
    - Samoilov, E. F.: "Kak ustroena nasha planeta-zemlia:, 1956 (Box 41, Folder 1022)
    - Saninian, Suren: "Nedorazumenie", [1963?] (Box 41, Folder 1023)
    - Seduro, Vladimir Il'ich
      See: Siadura, Vladzimir, Box 43, folder 1063
    - Semenchenko: "Barin. Khveda", n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1024)
    - Semënov-Tian-Shanskii, Valerii Petrovich: "Staryi sad; istoricheskaia byl'" (Box 41, Folder 1025)
    - Serge, Victor: "Existentialisme". In French, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 1026)
    - Shaikevich, Anatolii Efimovich: "Most vzdokhov cherez Nevu", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1026a-33)
    - Sharshun, Sergei Ivanovich: "IAno Grustneishii... Pervaia kniga epopei Vslepuiu, 1939-56 (Box 42, Folder 1034-38)
    - Shcherbatov, Sergei, kniaz'
      - "Mysli... khudozhnika otorvanogo ot rodiny", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1039)
      - "Vospominania", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1040)
    - [Shestov, Leo]: "[Interv'iu[?] s Shestovym]" Shestov's answers. Unidentified interviewer, 1933-38 (Box 42, Folder 1041)
    - Shik, Aleksandr
      - "Dva vystrela. K 150-letiiu dnia rozhdeniia Lermontova", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1042)
      - "Gogol' v Peterburge", [1958?] (Box 42, Folder 1043)
      - "Parizhskie dni Gogolia", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1044)
    - Shishkov, F.: "I plakali berëzy zhenchuzhnymi slezami", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1045)
    - Shmelev, I. S. (Ivan Sergeevich)
      - "Dusha rodiny", 1924 (Box 42, Folder 1046)
      - "Slovo na chestvovanii I. A. Bunina", [1953?] (Box 42, Folder 1047)
      - "Soldaty", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1048)
      - "Svet vechnyi; razskas zemlemera", 1937 (Box 42, Folder 1049)
    - Shneerov, M. M.
      - "Moi pervyi pobeg... ", n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1050)
      - "V tsarstve tenei; otryvok iz biografii", 1957 (Box 42, Folder 1051-52)
    - Shteingel', Pavel Leonardovich: "Andron; kavkazkaia byl'", [1961] (Box 43, Folder 1053-56)
    - Shtepa, Konstantin Feodos'evich
      - "Krizis idei", n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1057)
      - "Krizis partii", n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1058)
      - "Ot Marksa k Stalinu", n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1059)
      - "Propaganda antiamerikanizma... " (Box 43, Folder 1060-61)
      - "Tret'e zveno dialekticheskoi triady v razvitii sovetskoi istoricheskoi nauki", n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1062)
    - Siadura, Vladzimir: "K probleme renessansa i barokko v Belorussii", n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1063)
    - Sibiriakov, M. I.: "V otpusk na rodinu", 1951 (Box 43, Folder 1064)
    - Sinevirskyi, Nikolai, pseud.
      - "Chudo v bol'shom gorode; povest'", 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1065-66)
      - "Mirnye liudi", 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1067-71)
    - Singer, Isaak Bashevis: "Ogon'; rasskaz", n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1072)
    - Skorniakov, Viktor: "V tupike", [1951] (Box 43, Folder 1073)
    - Smolenskii, Vladimir: "Mistika Aleksandra Bloka", 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1074)
    - Sobolev, Petr Grigor'evich
      - "Legenda drevnego goroda", 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1075)
      - "Na severe Rossii", 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1076)